SR. JAVA/QUARTZ DEVELOPER

Professional Summary

Over 9 Years of professional experience on Systems Analysis, Design, Development, Performance Optimization, Documentation and Integration of complex Client/Server, Portals and Web Based n-tier architecture systems. Have excellent analytical, problem-solving, decision-making Excellent Communication, Interpersonal, analytical skills and easy adaptation with changing technology. Having Experience with Bloomberg API like TSAPI and B-PIPE, Reuters API(RFA), Open Message Model(OMM), Data Feed RDF, RMDS as well as Value bond, Bond Desk and Market Axxess Strong understanding in Core Java concepts such as AWT, Swing, JFC, Java Applets, Multithreading, Network Programming, TCP/IP Socket Programming, RMI, HTTP/HTTPS/FTP programming, Java Collection API, Java Generics, Java Reflection Skills

Java AWS
Work History
Sr. Java/Quartz Developer, 08/2012 to Current
Walt Disney Co. – Washington, MA

- Experience with J2EE architecture (JSP, Servlet, EJB, JDBC, JNDI, JMS, and JAXB) as well as Struts, Tiles, Spring, Direct Web Remoting (DWR), Google Web Toolkit(GWT), AJAX, Web services, XML, Hibernate, IBatis and UML modeling.
- Strong experience in Enterprise Messaging Systems like JMS, TIBCO EMS, RV, IBM MQ Series, and AMPS as well as Caching like RV Cache, Oracle Coherence Cache Experience with Application and Web Servers such as Apache Tomcat, JBoss, WebSphere, WebSphere Portal Server, BEA WebLogic, Glassfish Server Hand On experience on Tibco Spotfire, Web Methods, Enterprise Web Methods Monitor Experience in OO design patterns and J2EE core patterns Model view Controller (MVC), DAO, DTO, Business Delegate, Service Locator, Session Façade, Front Controller, Singleton Expertise in Object Oriented Analysis and Design (OOAD) analyzing and developing UML, Different Diagrams as well as Agile Methodologies like Test Driven Development (TDD), SCRUM, Xtreme Programming (XP) Developed and implement Service Oriented Architecture (SOA) using XML Web Services (SOAP, WSDL, and UDDI) and used SOAP processing engine such as Apache Axis and used open source service framework such as Apache CXF.
- Working experience in writing SQL and PL/SQL queries, functions, stored procedures, triggers and creating table/views for various RDBMS including Oracle, Sybase, Microsoft SQL Server and MySQL as well as open source ORDBMS Postgres.
- Working with Version control like CVS, Microsoft Visual Source safe, Clear Case, Subversion, Perforce.

Team Lead/Sr. Java/J2EE Developer, 03/2012 to 08/2012 Walt Disney Co. â€" Houston, TX

Project

Team Lead/Sr. Java/J2EE Developer , 08/2010 to 02/2012 Walt Disney Co. â€" Chicago , IL

• Europe/US Trading, Retail Trading Platform

Senior Software Engineer , 09/2009 to 08/2010 Amgen Inc. $\hat{a} \in$ Atlanta , GA

- Trade Services is trade capture and processing service used in FID by product lines globally Global IRP (USB & GBB & Zurich), Credit, FI Derivatives (FIRM) and Equities (Mira).
- It is n-tier application, with Java code deployed on web servers that connects to an Oracle database at the backend.
- Responsibilities

Senior Software Engineer , 01/2008 to 09/2009 Amgen Inc. –Denver , CO

Project

Senior Software Engineer , 01/2007 to 12/2007 Amgen Inc. – Austin , TX

Project

Software Engineer, 03/2006 to 01/2007 Applied Information Sciences, Inc. â€"Reston, VA

Project

Software Engineer, 10/2005 to 03/2006 Sarjen System Pvt. Ltd â€" City, STATE

Project

Software Engineer , 12/2004 to 10/2005 Konark Life Science Pvt. Ltd – City , STATE • Project

Software Engineer , 01/2004 to 12/2004 World Gaming â€" City , STATE

Project

Education

Master of Science: Computer Science, 2006

ICFAI University - City, State Computer Science & Application BS: Mathematics, 1 2002

Mathematics

Sun Certified Java Programmer (SCJP) with 93% in 2007 Sun Certified Web component Developer (SCWCD) with 94% in 2008:

Certifications SCJP

SCWCD

Skills

Adobe, Agile, ANT, Ant 1.5, Apache, API 7.2, API, application development, approach, ATG Dynamo, ATG Dynamo 4.5.1, ATG Dynamo, Bloomberg, business process, change management, client-server, Content Management, Controller, Credit, encryption, CSS, Client, clients, Customer service, Version Control, CVS, DAO, Database, Derivatives, Designing, DHTML, documentation, DOM, Macromedia Dreamweaver, Dynamo application server, Eclipse, Eclipse 6, Editor, E-mail, email, EJB, Equities, fast, fetch, Financial, Fixed Income, functional, GUI, HTML, HTTP, IBM, IBM MQ Series, IBM WebSphere, WebSphere, IDE, J2EE, Java, JSP, Java Swing, Java Beans, Beans, Java Scripts, JavaScript, Java Script, JBoss, JDBC, JMS, JNDI, knowledge management, Languages, layout, Linux, Log4J, Logic, Market, Messaging, access, eXchange, Mail, money, MS Office, Office, Microsoft Visio, Windows 2000, 2000, Windows 98, NT, Windows XP, modeling, MVC, MySQL, My SQL, Enterprise, Networks, OO design, OOAD, Object Oriented Analysis and Design, Operating Systems, Oracle, Oracle database, DB, Developer, PL/SQL, Oracle 8, Oracle 8i, page, Postgres, Pricing, producer, coding, Programmer, Programming, Python, Rational Rose, RDBMS, real time, Retail, Reuters, SDLC, securities, Servers, Servlet, Servlets, SOAP, Software Development, Sun Solaris, SOP, Visual Source Safe, Specification, MS- SQL Server, Microsoft SQL Server, SQL, SQL Server 2000, strategy, Structured, Struts 1.3, Struts 2.0, Struts, Sun, Swing, Sybase, tables, TCP/IP, Tibco, Tomcat, Trading floor, trading system, UML, UNIX, Unix Shell scripts, USB, user interface, validation, View, Vista, Web Servers, web server, Web Development, WebLogic, Windows 2000 Server, workbench, Workflow, Written, XML, XSL, XSLT